A Guide to the Pulaski County Court Documents, 1837-1886
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Pulaski County Court Documents 1837-1886
Special Collections, Kegley Library
1984.1
1 folder.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by V. Hubbard in 1984.
Scope and Content
These records were initially housed in the vertical file collection of the Kegley Library; in 2004 they were removed and processed as a manuscript collection. Documents include miscellaneous records connected with the transactions of the Pulaski County, Virginia, County Court dating from 1837 to 1886. Included are summons, apprenticeship appointment, a deposition, and account statement.
Contents List
- Folder 1. Pulaski County Court Documents. 1837-1886, 9 items.
  - Apprenticeship agreement between J. G. Cecil and James Madison regarding Mary Warden. 10 February 1837., 1 p.
    Apprenticeship agreement between J. G. Cecil, Overseer of the Poor, Montgomery County, Virginia and James Madison regarding apprenticeship of nine year old Mary Warden. Madison agrees to teach and employ said girl in ordinary household and family concerns such as females are accustomed to and not put her to the hard and laborious service with outdoors required of boys and moreover that he will cause the said Mary to be taught reading and writing distinctly as the law requires and to furnish the said apprentice girl with food, raiment, and other fare.
  - Summons for Page Farmer. 7 April 1848., 1 p.
    Farmer was indicted for permitting slaves to unlawfully assemble on his tenement.
  - Appointment of John Brown as Surveyor of Public Road. 7 June 1866., 1 p.
    Appointment of John Brown as Surveyor of the Public Road from Tazewell to the Rubush place. Workers assigned to Brown included Jno. M. Hoge, 12 Negroes, William Burton, H. Vickers and 2 sons, one Negro on Tyler Cecil's place, Rufus Morgan and 1 Negro, Charles Burton, Jno. Brown and 2 Negroes, Giles Tinkle, William Anderson and son and Negro, William Hendron, and Joseph Fleman.
  - Report of Commissioners in case of Henry C. Wysor and John H. Sharpe and J. Miller. 9 February 1871., 4 p.
    The Pulaski County Court appointed John D. Howe, John T. Whaling, J. K. Miller, and William Anderson as Commissioners to go upon the said tract of land and make partition thereof by laying off and assigning to the defendant John H. Sharp one equal third part of the said tract in value and to the said Henry C. Wysor and J. M. Miller in one parcel two equal third parts in value and report their proceedings to the Court.
  - Promissory note between John Weddle and Wall & Wysor Company. 9 February 1881., 1 p.
  - Account Statement of Pulaski County Board of Supervisors. 1883., 2 p.
    Statement of Pulaski County Board of Supervisors in account with Dr. J. W. Farmer for services rendered in care of smallpox patients.
  - Summons to Julia Hall. 3 July 1883., 2 p.
    Summons to Julia Hall by Pulaski County Court for assault and battery upon Susan Summers.
  - Deposition of Ambrose Robinson in John W. Farmer vs. County of Pulaski. 7 August 1883., 8 p.
    Robinson testified on behalf of Dr. John W. Farmer who maintained that he lost potential revenue while caring for smallpox patients.
  - Bond notice to James Stuart as administrator of Sarah Stuart estate. 24 August 1886., 2 p.
    The Pulaski County Court notified Stuart that a new bond would be required of him as administrator of Sarah Stuart's estate in a greater penalty than current bond.